这一周的新闻报道让人难过
It's been a harrowing week in the news,
所以现在是时候来点更加轻松幽默的了
so now it's something much lighter and more fun.
是时候让新西兰人民最爱的流行文化记者
It's time for New Zealand's favorite pop culture reporter,
大卫 法瑞尔出马了
David Farrier.
你到目前为止对新西兰什么印象
What do you make of New Zealanders so far?
我吗 我觉得他们 他们很友好
Me? Uh, I think that they're... They've been nice.
大家都挺酷的
Everyone has been cool so far.
你在这最想实现什么
What's the main thing you're trying to achieve here?
因为很显然你都创造了一些
Because obviously you've created a bit of a--
我想生存
survival.
他死了
He's dead.
-现在我们准备要转圈了 -是的
- Now we're gonna spin around. - Yeah.
哇 天啊
Whoa! Holy!
真累人 哇
It's so tiring. Whoa!
你得过什么外号
And what's your nickname that you've got now?
驴夫人
The donkey lady.
小心 我们要
Look out! Oh, look, we're going
让一名记者挨踢了
- to have a reporter kicked.
踢得真狠啊
It's quite a kick.
我说不出来曾经采访过
I can't say I've ever interviewed anyone
看起来和你一样的人
that looks exactly like you before.
真的吗
Really?
我的职业生涯就是观察
I've made a career out of looking at the weird
这个世界奇葩的一面
- and bizarre side of life.
所以当我网上发现了奇怪的视频
So when I discovered a strange video online,
我就知道下个故事有着落了
I knew I'd found my next story.
很好 很好
It's good. It's good.
一家叫做简 奥布莱恩传媒的公司
An American company called Jane o'brien media
正在筹划每月一次的活动
was running a monthly event.
全球各地的年轻运动员都可以申请参加
Young athletes from anywhere on the planet could apply.
如果入选他们就免费飞到洛杉矶
If selected they got free flights to la,
在高档酒店住四晚 还可以拿到1500美元现金酬劳
four nights in a really nice hotel and $1500 cash.
这就是搔痒忍耐力比赛
It was called competitive endurance tickling.
大家现在和搔忍赛在一起
You're with the cet,
我们是搔痒忍耐力比赛的队伍
a competitive endurance tickling group we got here.
首先 我想和你说
And, uh, first of all I'd like to give a shout to you,
简 奥布莱恩传媒举办了这一切
Jane o'brien media, for making this happen.
-谢谢 简 -我们都很感谢
- Thanks, Jane. - We all appreciate it.
滚蛋
Fuck off!
伙计们 天哪
Guys! Oh, my god!
他们的脸书主页很受欢迎
Their Facebook page was popular,
有成千上万个赞
with thousands of likes.
而且大家都穿着阿迪达斯
And with everyone in Adidas gear,
看起来好像这是某种挠痒比赛联盟
it seemed to be some kind of tickling league.
这是我见过最奇怪的运动
It was one of the strangest sports I'd seen.
不要
No!
当然了 我告知简 奥布莱恩传媒
So, of course, I told Jane o'brien media
我想做个采访
I'd like to do an interview.
没收到许可与否的回应 我收到了这个
Instead of getting a yes or no, I got this.
非常无礼直白地告诉您
"To be brutally frank,
与同性恋记者的合作
association with a homosexual journalist
并非我们可容忍的行为
is not something we will embrace.
我们非常不想有同性恋立场的参与者
We desperately do not want a homosexual participant base
申请该项目
applying for this project.
我担心的是你的采访风格 粉丝群
My concern is that your journalistic style, fan base,
以及你在自己国家的声誉
and reputation in your own country.
简 奥布莱恩传媒 黛比 库恩 致意
Regards, Debbie kuhn, Jane o'brien media."
回复很奇怪
It was a strange response,
尤其是考虑到这项运动看着有点
especially considering the sport did seem slightly...
基
Gay.
在接下来的几周 黛比和简一直发邮件来
And over the coming weeks, Debbie and Jane kept e-mailing.
这项赛事本质上是一项
"The competitive reality tickling
仅限于
is a passionately
异性恋运动员的忍耐力活动
and exclusively heterosexual athletic endurance activity.
我们最近拜读了谷歌到的
We have recently read a googled article about the knowledge
您和您同性伴侣生活起居的那篇
of your living with a homosexual partner
名噪一时的文章
becoming quite a stir in New Zealand."
这世上其他人并没有到处
"The remainder of the globe does not in all corners
散布要接纳你的生活方式的观念
share some of the more liberal acceptance of your lifestyle."
与我而言 任何与同性恋有关的
"To me anything concerning homosexuality
都属于客观失调[该说法源自于天主教 认为同性恋取向是客观失调]
is at best an objective disorder."
以你为耻 小新西兰基 死基佬
"Shame on you!" "Little gay kiwis." "Faggot."
考虑到简传媒制作的东西
It was hard to take the insults seriously,
很难让人对以上辱骂当真
given what Jane was producing.
甚至正相反 这使我比以往更加好奇
If anything, it made me more curious than ever.
您的呼叫已被转接至
Your call has been forwarded
语音信箱 简 奥布莱恩传媒
to the voicemail for Jane o'brien media.
既然没人接听电话
With no one picking up the phone,
我找来了我的极客朋友朋友迪兰
I got my geeky friend Dylan to do some digging
来挖挖这家神秘的公司
into this mysterious company
还有这位特别咄咄逼人的女士有什么料
and this overly aggressive woman.
我得滚动一下 可以开始了
So, I'm going to just scroll up. So here we go.
这就是简 奥布莱恩传媒的网址
So, it's janeobrienmedia.Com.
注册在Nederdietsen旗下
It's registered to nederdietsen.
他发现简 奥布莱恩传媒
He discovered that while Jane o'brien media
好像是在美国境外运营
seemed to be operated out of America,
归一家叫Nederdietsen的德国公司所有
it was owned by a company in Germany called nederdietsen,
该公司拥有和挠痒有关的300多个域名
which owned nearly 300 domain names all related to tickling.
随着调查的进一步深入
This tickling wormhole was getting deeper,
所以迪兰和我在网上用博客记录了我们的发现
so Dylan and I blogged about what we'd found.
回响还不错
So, the pay's good.
什么 好吧 等等
What? Okay, hold on.
我们的故事引起了很多人的关注
Our story got a lot of attention,
被摘录到了新闻即时阅网
being picked up on websites like reddit
和一个美国的播客上[类似广播的形式 但是方便回放]
and an American podcast.
-后退 后退 -当我说
- Back up. Back up. - When I say
挠痒比赛的时候 你觉得我在说什么事情
competitive tickling, what do you think I'm talking about?
我是说 我觉得你在说
I mean, I think you're talking about, uh,
某种有组织的运动
some sort of organized sport--
-是的 -挠痒运动
- Yeah. - ...Of tickling.
主要就是这周这事在互联网上热度爆表
Basically what happened was this kind of blew up
因为一个新西兰的伙计
on the Internet this week, because a dude in New Zealand,
一名记者 像是 在脸书主页上的事吧
a reporter, like, happened across this Facebook page.
但只是为了好玩么 他们只是
But is it just for fun? They just...
很显然就是好玩吧
I mean, obviously it's just for fun?
就是为了好玩吗
Is it just for fun?
是挠痒
- It's tickling.
抱歉 我没记得问过挠痒的问题
Sorry, I don't think that question's ever been asked
挠痒的问题就像火星问题似的
about tickling before. It's like a martian question
就是好玩么
- about tickling. - "Is it for fun?"
人们对我们的发现很感兴趣
People were so interested by what we discovered,
迪兰和我决定就这件非常之奇怪的
Dylan and I decided to make a documentary
事件做一个纪录片
about this utterly bizarre subject.
两周之后
Two weeks later,
我们收到了简 奥布莱恩传媒从纽约发来的律师函
we heard from Jane o'brien's New York attorney,
来自罗密欧 萨尔塔
Romeo salta.
他最近因为参与一件
He'd recently made headlines in a case
同性恋色情明星
involving a gay porn star
将受害者碎尸
who chopped a man up
并邮寄尸块给政客的案件而声名大噪
and mailed his body parts to some politicians.
事情当然没有就此变得无聊
Things certainly weren't getting any less weird.
他信中告诉我们停下所作所为
His letter told us to stop what we were doing, or else.
很快我们收到了来自萨尔塔的邮件告知我们
Soon we were receiving e-mails from salta telling us
已经对我们的行为提交了诉讼文件
that legal action had been filed in the us.
我没有钱雇佣新西兰律师
I had no money to hire a New Zealand lawyer,
更不用说面对美国司法系统
let alone face the American justice system.
然后 最妙的是 简 奥布莱恩传媒告诉我们
Then, to top it all off, Jane o'brien media told us
他们派三人穿过大半个地球 正从纽约飞到
they were flying three people across the world from New York
新西兰和我们见面
to New Zealand to see us.
他们对阻止做这个纪录片这事很是认真
They're clearly serious about stopping this documentary.
简没说他们要乘哪个航班到达
Jane wouldn't tell us what flight they were arriving on,
但是她告诉了我们具体日期
but she did tell us the day.
所以早晨5点开始 我就在到达区等他们
So from 05:00 am, I waited at arrivals.
不知道会发生什么
Not sure what to expect,
我用一个彩虹颜色的标志
I figured I'd disarm the situation
缓和了气氛
with a rainbow-colored sign.
事情进展的如何
How's it going?
我感觉我做了一个很棒的欢迎标志
I thought I'd make up a good welcoming sign.
你好吗 先生
Good. How are you, sir?
没关系 旅途如何
That's all right. I thought I'd arrive. How was the flight?
很好 新西兰航空吗
Oh, good. Air New Zealand?
很好 嘿 大家伙
Oh, good. Hey, guys.
我是凯文 见到你很高兴 大卫 见到你很高兴
Kevin, nice to meet you, sir. David. Nice to meet you.
可以 把这个当礼物送你
You can. I gift this to you.
用标志的标准来评定的话 相当不错了
As a sign, I thought it was pretty good.
那么 咱们排个时间这周见见吧
Well, look, let's line up a time to meet this week.
明天吗
Tomorrow?
-我们今天需要休息 你明天有空么
好 明天没问题
Okay, tomorrow works well.
- 很感谢来见我们
没问题 这是新西兰的礼仪
Oh, that's okay. It's the New Zealand hospitality.
你可以到那找我
You can get me there.
嗯 咱们从始至终都在拍摄
Yeah, we're just rolling from the beginning. Yeah, yeah.
好 在新西兰是这样的
Okay. We've got a thing in New Zealand,
我们可以在公众场合进行拍摄
we're okay to film in public spaces.
所以我只是在一路拍下来
So I'm just following the journey.
好 没问题 我们
Okay, all right. Well, we're--
不是
It's not--
我们在拍纪录片
Okay. Well, I mean, we're shooting a documentary,
我们会继续 只是
so we'll keep... it's a--
呃
Mm.
好
Okay.
我们在新西兰公开场合可以拍摄的
Okay. We're okay to film in public spaces in New Zealand,
所以我们这里也拍了
so we're doing that here.
好吧 我们会很快见面的
All right, we'll see you soon.
-好 听起来不错
- Okay, sounds good.
好吧 回见
All right, see you soon.
别担心 很快就可以坐下来谈谈
No worries. We'll talk soon.
喂 马尔科 我是大卫 法瑞尔 你怎么样啦
Hey, Marko. It's Dave farrier. How are you?
很好 你怎么在奥克兰落脚的
Yeah, good. How are you settling into Auckland?
没 听着不错
Okay. No, that sounds good to me, I think.
只是 迪兰和我都谈过了 我们都没信心
Just, Dylan and I both talked, and we just weren't confident,
觉着径直走进一间屋子
or didn't think it was a good idea
那样不好 也许只是文化上的问题吧
just to go straight to a room. Maybe it's a cultural thing.
但是会议室
But a conference room
你选的 好吧
- um, of your choosing,
在不在希尔顿都没问题
Whether it's at the Hilton or elsewhere, is absolutely fine.
嗯
And, um...
没问题
Sure.
凯文没有很好没有很好的说服迪兰
Kevin didn't take to Dylan very well
他想单独见我
and wants to meet me alone.
我迅速做了这个隐蔽的电子设备
I quickly make this covert piece of technology.
咖啡杯里的相机
A camera in a coffee cup.
结局是什么呢 你最后得到了什么
What's the end game here? What do you get at the end
你得到了想要的一切吗
or even if you get everything you want?
我们在这冒这险干嘛
Mm. Mm. - And what are we risking here?
我们真的希望那个有钱的家伙
You know, do we really want someone coming after you
对你穷追不舍吗
with all that money?
我这辈子认识很多有钱人
I've known a lot of rich people in my life.
我为其中很多人打过工
I've worked for a lot of them.
他们不吃我们这一套
They don't work by the same set of rules.
他们神龙见首不见尾
They don't dangle them out of buildings any more,
因为没有这个必要
but they don't have to.
就是问题所在 他们控告你
And that's the thing. They start suing,
你却只得半途而废
and you're done halfway through or a quarter of the way through
因为辩护的花费使你债台高筑
because it costs so much to defend yourself.
所以 本质上来说
So unless... Essentially, I mean,
如果我们不拍了 我们就完蛋了
unless we stop the doco, we're gonna be fucked.
真的 归根结底就是这样
Really. It seems that's what it comes down to.
我不会直接把话挑明
I'm not gonna use those words directly,
因为这样太不明智了
because that wouldn't be prudent.
但是 重申一下 除非你收手
But... let me rephrase. Unless you stopped...
除非我们能够找到改善现状的办法
Unless we can figure out a way to ameliorate that situation,
我们退一步
we all are.
面临诉讼和以及财力雄厚的公司
Facing lawsuits and a company with deep pockets,
我在想我们是否应该放手[据导演所说 诉讼求偿额高达四千万刀]
I wondered if we should just walk away.
但是迪兰也深陷其中
But Dylan was part of this now
他不愿意向恶势力低头
and didn't want to give in to a bunch of bullies.
迪兰想要单刀赴会吗
Dylan wants to pursue this on his own?
额 我从他说的话里面推断出来的
Uh, I gather from what he's saying, yeah.
好 嗯 如果迪兰想这么做的话
Okay. Um, if Dylan wants to do that,
迪兰 他会这么做的
Dylan does... Dylan will do that.
如果你想明哲保身的话 离开得远远的
If you don't want to do that, then just walk away from it.
是的
Yeah.
我会 那只会针对迪兰了
And I will... Dylan will be dealt with accordingly.
学校怎样
How was school?
重点是 大卫 你懂得
The main thing, David, you know,
我想告诉你的是
that I wanted to tell you is that
你觉得你很聪明
I think that you're brilliant.
事业风顺
And that you have a great career.
因此我 很高兴知道
So I was really, really happy to find out
你愿意全身而退
that you wanted just to distance yourself from it.
但是不懂迪兰为什么就不愿意呢
And I don't understand why Dylan would not want to.
正如凯文说的 也是我最担心的
What I'm worried about too, I know Kevin says,
好 如果他执意这么做的话
"Well, if he wants to go ahead with it,
就让他去吧
let him go ahead with it."
但是他会成头号靶子 相信我
But he'll become a real target, and believe me,
让他出尽洋相
it will be really ugly for him.
我会 我也不想看到事情变成那样
And I would... I would hate to see that too,
因为我知道他有家庭
because I know he has a family
你知道他可能是个不错的小伙子
and, you know, he's probably, uh, a good bloke down deep.
在我生命中从未因为挠痒
I've never heard threats like this in my life,
有过这样的威胁
and all of this over some tickling!
凯文和马尔科飞回美国
Kevin and Marko fly back to America.
几天后 迪兰和我也去了美国
And a few days later, Dylan and I follow.
被超乎想象的金钱打压欺侮
Something about bullies with way too much money
让我不能就这么放弃
has convinced me I shouldn't drop it.
加上 我们知道
Plus, we think there's a
这个星期有挠痒赛
competitive tickling shoot happening this week.
我们联系视频里的将近一百位男孩
We've reached out to nearly a hundred boys in the videos,
但是他们都不愿意出面
but they all seem too nervous to talk.
最后有个名叫TJ的同意见面
Finally tj agrees to meet us.
我跟凯文 克拉克在洛杉矶市中心某地方碰面
We met Kevin Clarke downtown la somewhere.
我不记得它具体在哪 但是个工作室
I can't remember exactly where it was at, but it was a studio.
看起来很正常
He seemed pretty normal at the time.
第一次见他 他有点
My first impression of him, you know, he was just, like,
有点奇怪
kind of... Kind of a little weird.
你知道那时我还小
You know, I was young at the time,
没想太多
didn't think nothing of it,
我满脑子就是 赞 2000美元唉
and I was like, "Cool." You know, $2000 or whatever,
耶 太赞了
"Yeah. It's gonna be cool."
那段时间家里经济困难
It was actually a hard time for my family.
家人有得癌症的
A family member of mine was going through cancer,
日子紧巴巴的
and money was tight at the household.
我有点绝望
So I was a little bit desperate
有了这点钱 一边工作
at the time as well for money, working on the side,
还能做点喜欢的 因此当我看到美元符号
and doing what I can. So when I heard this dollar sign,
灵光一闪 好 我该这么做
I was like, "Yeah," You know, "I'll definitely do that."
然后我走进去
And then I went inside
注意到房间里面站满了人
and noticed that it was all guys in there.
但是当我这样做 哦 该死
And that's when I was like, "Oh, dang!" Like...
我不知怎么就被绑住了
And I didn't know I was gonna get tied down.
我不知道会这是为什么
I had no idea what it'd be for.
老实说 我就想 好了 发生什么事情
Honestly, I was like, "Okay, what?"
在那时我在想 很好
At that point I was like, "All right,
你知道吗 木已成舟
you know what? It's already going down.
我不知道会发生什么
I don't really know what it's for,
希望别太出格
but hopefully it never gets out."
不不不 没那么过分
No, no, no. Not any fuckin'...
卧槽 真的是挠痒
Ah! Fuck! That actually tickles, dude.
卧槽
Ah! Fuck!
这么多处刑方式
Being violated on so many different levels right now.
还有其他运动员 做格斗的
There was other athletes. There was mma guys.
有个健美运动者
There was a bodybuilder,
还有一些演员 平常的演员
and then there was a couple of actors, normal actors.
有些我还在广告里见过
I've seen some of them on commercials,
电视广告 一般的家伙
TV commercials. Normal guys.
看起来跟一般人没区别
Like, completely normal people.
放开我的脚
Get the fuck off my feet!
简直是酷刑
It was a torture project.
这就是凯文 克拉克告诉我的
That's what I believe Kevin Clarke told me.
这跟军事手段
There was something to do with
或者同类事物有关
even a military tactic, or something like that.
他要
He was gonna do...
我认为简在做研究
I think he said Jane was doing a project
关于将挠痒用于军事手段的研究
on using tickling as a military tactic.
那时 我
And at that point, I...
简直是瞎扯 有懂吗
I knew it was complete bullshit, you know?
我想 好 军事上将会用挠痒
I was like, "Okay, the military is gonna use tickling
做酷刑吗
as a torture tactic?"
卧槽
Fuck!
什么时候看到视频了
When did the video come back to get you?
大概持续一年时间 也许更长一点
About a year, maybe a little more, ago.
看一些旧文章
to read old articles
想看看哪个队在文章标题或者训练里
or see what teams might have listed me in an article
提到我
or try-outs.
吓到我的是 油管上有个视频
And to my surprise, a video was on YouTube.
你好 我是TJ 我在挠痒比赛
Hello. I'm tj, and I'm here on a tickling competition.
额 第一个问题是 你是挠痒痒爱好者吗
And, uh, first question is: "Are you ticklish?"
嗯 如果我不是 我就不会来了 所以
Well, obviously I'm ticklish if I'm here, so,
这问题真可笑 但是 额
that's kind of a silly question. But, uh...
我真的坐在了镜头前
It was just me sitting in front of the camera
谈论怎么挠痒痒
talking about the, uh, tickling process.
奇怪 我在想 还不坏
Just weird things. And so I was like, "Okay, it's not that bad."
当你被问 你喜欢挠痒痒吗
"When you are asked, 'are you ticklish?'
你会怎么回答 为什么
how do you normally respond and why?"
通常 我说 不 我不喜欢挠痒痒
Normally, I say, "No, I'm not ticklish."
所以我给简发了邮件 请求撤下视频
So I emailed Jane and asked her to take the video down.
她没有回复
She didn't ever reply.
因此我决定自己解决
So I took the matters into my own hands,
我找油管说
and I, uh, told YouTube that
他们非法使用我的名字
uh, they're illegally using my name.
因此油管撤下视频 噩梦开始了
So YouTube took the video down. That's when it all started.
现在我就想笑
"Now, I am laughing."
我不觉得你搞定这件事了
"I don't think you've grasped the magnitude
事情反而闹大了
of what you have provoked."
我想知道你怎么收拾摊子
"I'm interested to see how you handle the fallout.
迄今为止一团糟 此致 黛比 库恩
So far, badly." "Regards, Debbie j. Kuhn."
这个叫黛博拉的人闯入我的生活
That's when this Deborah person popped into my life.
意味着失去了一切控制
I mean, just all hell broke loose.
你能找到的视频网站 都有这个视频
Every kind of video search you can find, it was up there.
他出现在我的邮箱
And then it pops up in my emails,
更是在油管
and then it pops up more on YouTube,
哪里都有它
and it just starts appearing everywhere.
这个视频 所有的视频
This video... Just, all of them.
一个接一个出现
All of them start blowing up.
还有恐吓 它说 小心
And there was threats. It said, "Watch out!
不要让你家人看见
Your family better watch out
会给你祖宗抹黑
because we're gonna put your last name to shame.
你什么时候搜索你的姓 视频自动弹出
Any time you search your last name, it's gonna pop up."
赤裸裸的威胁
Like, direct threats.
他们还建了网站
They ended up making a website,
放了我个人信息
putting my personal information:
名字 住址
My name, my address,
私人电话 邮箱
my personal phone number, my email address,
愚蠢的谎言
all with just dumb lies.
然后黛比 库恩出场
Then Debbie kuhn starts going off on me left and right,
给我当教练的高中发邮件
sending emails to the high school that I coach at.
我作为前任雇主向您发送这份消息
"I have additional information as a past employer.
我不想要这家伙在您的队伍里
You don't want this guy in your league.
你受得了媒体报导这个
Can you afford the distraction, the press,
出柜男性同性恋挠痒爱好者的骚扰吗
with an outed gay guy having a male tickling fetish,
他喜欢挠痒 被挠痒
in which he likes to tickle and be tickled
还被其他同性恋运动员和健美运动员绑起来
by tied-up other gay athletes and bodybuilders?"
完全是污蔑 说我是瘾君子
False accusations, saying I'm a drug addict
说我的是娈童者 说我是同性恋等等
and I was a child molester and I'm gay, and this and that,
完全没有这回事
which none of those things have ever been true.
我原本多自信
I've always been very proud.
走到哪 都在为自己骄傲
The way I walk around, I'm proud of who I am.
你知道我在说什么吗 就是说
You know what I mean? So to speak.
我很为自己运动员的身份感到骄傲
I'm confident in myself as an athlete,
我是一个人 一个运动员
as a person, as a player.
但是当我训练时
But when I'd go to try-outs,
只想到
the first thing I would think about is,
完了 要是教练看过视频怎么办
"Well, I wonder if these coaches have looked up that video?"
该来的还是来了
And it's happened. It has happened.
我被踢出橄榄球队了
I've been released from football teams.
他们告诉我原因了
They've told me, uh,
曾经我是队里那个位置最优秀的运动员
that I'm the best player on that team at that position,
但是因为视频的影响
but because it is a distraction for the media,
他们不需要这样的关注
they don't need that attention
他们会找别人
and they'll go with somebody
因为他们不想去解释
else 'cause they don't feel like explaining it.
要知道 因为这件事
You know, and I've actually
我沾上了不少麻烦
dealt with a lot of things because of it.
钱没了 工作黄了 骚扰不断
It's cost me money, it's cost me jobs, it's caused me harassment,
正如黛比 库恩和简 奥布莱恩所愿
which is exactly what Debbie kuhn and Jane o'brien wanted.
所以 我说 无论怎样 他们赢了
So, I mean, more or less in that aspect, they've won.
因简 奥布莱恩传媒而受到困扰的
It's obvious we're not the only ones being harassed
不止我们
by Jane o'brien media.
有许许多多像TJ网的网站
And there are so many websites made up like tj's
依旧存在
which seem to exist purely
羞辱那些挠痒者
to shame the guys who've been tickled.
这些视频怎么了 为什么她这么咄咄逼人
What goes on at these shoots, and why is she so aggressive?
迪兰在做一些调查
Dylan's been doing some research,
他似乎知道下一次拍摄的地点
and he thinks he knows where the next shoot is happening.
我们监视工作室 想要发现
We stake out the studio, hoping to find out
挠痒痒比赛怎么进行
how a competitive tickling shoot goes down.
好 车来了
Okay, car.
又有一辆车 两辆
And another car. Two cars.
两辆了
Two cars.
你看得清车里情况吗
Can you see what the car's doing?
看不清他
I've lost him.
那是谁 -哦 马尔科
Who's that guy? - Oh, that's Marko.
是的 有四个人入镜了
Oh, yeah. And we've got four guys going in so far.
四个家伙
Four guys.
那家伙是新西兰人
That's the guy from New Zealand.
耶 那是凯文
Yep, there's Kevin.
窗户内笑声不断
We could hear laughter coming out of the vents.
几个小时后
It went on for hours,
男孩子们抽空在休息
the boys occasionally taking breaks.
实在是太诡异了
You know, this is actually fucking creepy as fuck.
就像是在开动员大会
Like, this feels to me like a pep talk.
是的
Yeah.
几天过去
As the day wraps up,
我想给凯文最后一个机会
I want to give Kevin one last chance
告诉我们里面发生了什么
to talk about what's going on.
还有诉讼在身
With pending lawsuits,
我小心翼翼不想沾惹是非
I'm cautious and don't want to storm into the studio.
他们没锁门
They haven't locked the door.
咱们过去吧
I think we go.
好吧 咱们走
All right. Okay, let's go.
一切还好吗 -还好
We're good? - Yep, we're good.
这边走
Come this way.
这边走吧 我们会被认出来
Here we go. We've been spotted.
哈喽 马尔科 嘿 大家好
Hello, Marko. Hey, guys.
亚当 进行得怎么样
Adam, how's it going?
先生 你好啊
Hello, sir.
这里不欢迎我们吗
We're not welcome here?
好吧 那 我们马上走
All right. Well, we'll head off.
你不想最后再聊聊或是什么吗
You don't want to do any final chats or anything?
最后一次机会
Last opportunity.
我们只能做到这样了
That's all we can do.
在贝尔维尤大道上右转
Turn right on bellevue Avenue,
第一个路口 右转
then take the first right.
我想 呃 在新西兰那事之后
I think... yeah, uh, after New Zealand and that,
我觉得这么说是很稳妥的 那就是我们没有
I think it's safe to say that we don't...
我们没做凯文或是马尔科的采访
We don't have an interview with Kevin or Marko.
我们当然也没让
And we certainly weren't getting
更多的参赛者上镜
any more of the competitors to talk on camera.
他们都吓坏了
They were all too terrified,
希望如果自己闭嘴 骚扰就会消失
hoping if they stayed quiet, the harassment would go away.
我是说 我们甚至只是在这儿
I mean, are we making the whole thing worse for everyone
就把大家的事情弄得更糟了吗
just by even being here?
嗯 我觉得有可能
Yeah. I think it's possible.
我担心这会让那些人的状况变得更糟
I worry that we make it worse for some people who...
那些已经度过最艰难时期的人 你明白吗
Who've gotten through the worst of it, you know?
嗯
Mm.
简 奥布莱恩显然对录像的目的
Jane o'brien clearly isn't being honest
有所隐瞒
about what the videos are for.
而且我确信 尽管穿着阿迪达斯
And I'm convinced that despite the Adidas gear,
这并不是一项实际的运动
it's not a real sport.
我找到了一名在佛罗里达
I've tracked down a man in Florida
也做被挠视频的男子
who also makes tickling videos,
不过 不像简 他很乐意谈论这些
but, unlike Jane, is more than happy to talk about it.
人们问我 痒痒的吸引力在哪儿
People ask me about what is the appeal of tickling?
这有点像鞭子和铁链 你明白的
It's kind of like the whips and chains, you know,
捆绑式性交之类的 有人被鞭打
bondage sort of thing, where somebody's getting flogged.
不过这也没到那个层次 你明白吗
But it's just really brought down a level, you know?
这有点像虐待
It's like kind of a sadistic
把你的意志施加到别人身上
exerting your will on someone else,
并让他们做出自己无法控制的事
and having them do something out of their control
比如大笑 却不能逃离
like laughing without being able to get away,
就像是 呃 挠痒折磨他们
as if it's, uh, tickle torture to them.
很多人似乎并不知道
And a lot of people don't seem to know
对痒痒的迷恋
about the tickling fetish.
你觉得这是不是有点 不为人知
Do you think it's a little bit more unknown?
喔 当然 肯定的
Oh, totally. Yeah, completely.
嗯 大多数人知道恋足癖
'Cause most people, you know, know about a foot fetish,
不过挠痒痒
um, but tickling?
大部分人就像 "喔 那也叫事"
Most people are like, "Oh, wow. Is that a thing?"
在1999年 我刚研究生毕业
It was in 1999. I had just gotten out of grad school,
所以我只弄到一个摄像机
you know, so I just got a video camera,
想了一个小小的商业计划
put together a little business plan,
和我一个朋友谈了谈
talked to one of my friends
他资助了我 我开了这家网站
and he financed me, when I started the site,
我想大概用了6000或是7000美元
I think for $6000 or $7000.
之后立刻得到了反响
It got pretty much an immediate response.
一年后 我挣到了足够我辞职
I was making enough after a year
专职做这个的钱
to quit my job and do it full-time.
所以 就这样
So this is it?
-就这样 -这个就是工作室
- This is it. - This is the studio.
-嗯 -椅子
- Mm-hm. - The chair.
还有更衣室 浴室
And then the changing room, bathroom.
那么 这所有的地方纯粹是为了挠痒痒
And so, this whole place is purely for the tickling?
没错
Yes.
有几个不同的场景 对吧
Oh, so you've got a few different spaces, right?
是啊
Yeah, yeah.
我以前不在我家里做所有这些
I used to do all this out of my house.
嗯
Yeah.
就是 你知道的 一群人进来
And then it was, you know, a parade of people coming in,
拍片后 我还得打扫干净
do all this, have to clean up.
在拍摄前必须清理干净
You know, have to clean it up before a shoot.
而这样一来 我可以一走了之
And this way I can walk away.
嗯 挺好的
Yeah, this is great.
就像 "我累了 回家去"
Like, "I'm tired. Going home."
你搞完了
You're done.
这是工作 对吧 就像工作 在家
Well, this is work, right? It's like work, home.
嗯哼 就是
Mm-hm. Exactly.
你以前为其他人做过类似的工作吗
Have you done stuff like this before for anyone else?
还是这是一件特别的事
Or this sort of a unique thing for you?
额 特别的
Uh, unique thing.
我从没为挠痒痒的网站工作过
I never worked for a tickling site before.
-好吧 -没有
- Okay. - No.
你听说要这么做之后 你怎么想的
And what did you first think when you got the pitch?
我是说 我大笑了会儿
I mean, I laughed about it.
就想 这不可能是认真的
I'm like, this can't be really serious,
人们不可能
like, people really can't...
享受看这个或者承受这个
Enjoy watching this or getting it done.
不过 呃我说 "为什么不呢"
But, um, I said, "Why not?"
我更像是个冒险者
You know, I'm more of like the risk-taker.
我更愿意说我做了什么而不是没做什么
I'd rather say I did something than didn't do something.
所以我躺下
So I came down,
真是有点紧张 不知道该期待什么
really was kind of nervous, didn't know what to expect.
然后 理查德让我放松
And then... But Richard put me at ease,
一旦你被困住 你就束手无策了
and once you're trapped in you're there.
所以呢 我是说 你可能也很享受
So, I mean, you might as well enjoy it.
好吧
All right.
好的 准备好了吗 -我想
Okay, ready? - I think you're...
今天对我下手轻点
Take it easy on me today.
好啊 好啊 当然
Yeah, yeah. Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
好极了
That's good.
-得珍惜我现在的自由 -是啊
- Got to enjoy my freedom now. - Yeah.
-因为我没办法 -挥手告别吧
- Because I cannot. - Wave goodbye.
我挣脱不了
I am not getting out.
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
挠痒痒的世界
The world of tickling.
所以 喘口气
So, catch your breath.
-喘了口气 -很好
- Breath caught. - Okay.
好吧
All right.
现在告诉大家 你是怎样的一个硬汉子
Now tell everybody what a tough guy you are.
继续
Just go.
住手
Stop.
我的天
Oh, my gosh.
讨厌死了
I hate this.
那么 你是什么时候
So when did you realize
意识到挠痒是件色情的事
that you found tickling to be an erotic thing?
当时我还很小
I was very young,
大概也就五岁或六岁 非常 非常小
you know, probably five or six. You know, very, very young.
你在卡通或者杂志里看到一些东西 你明白
You see something in a cartoon or a magazine that, you know,
作为一个小孩 你对那些东西很有兴趣
kind of interests you as a little kid,
而对我来说 就像
and for me it would be, you know, like,
卡通人物被挠痒或者被捆绑 或是
cartoon characters being tickled or tied up or,
你懂的 那种事
you know, that sort of thing.
而那些 让我觉得很刺激
And it would, you know, fascinate me,
不过我当时不知道为什么
but I had no idea why.
感觉怎么样
How do you feel?
我觉得好累
I feel tired.
-我觉得身上好多汗 -我要帮你拿些水吗
- I feel sweaty. - Can I get you some water?
好啊 喝点水应该好很多
Yeah, water would probably work.
我渐渐对这些 呃
I started to become comfortable with this, uh,
这种迷恋和这部分的我 感到很自在
fetish and this part of myself,
而之后 我开始真正意识到那是我的一部分
and started to really realize that it was a part of myself,
那时 我
when I...
我上了美国在线网
When I got on aol
搜索了我一直在寻找的内容
and then did a search for what I was looking for
然后发现 "喔
and found that, "Wow!
事实上
There's actually, you know, quite a lot of
有相当多其他人也热衷这个"
other people that are into this."
那是还是90年代末
At the time, the late '90s,
嗯 有人在留言板上发了很多帖
was, um, somebody that posted on the message boards a lot.
她说她的名字是特里 特里 挠痒
And she said her name was Terri, Terri tickle.
还有特里 迪西斯托 她放了真名
And Terri disisto, she put in what her real name was.
她总会放一张她自己的照片
She always had a picture of herself.
就那种金发碧眼的漂亮大学女孩
You know, a blonde, pretty, college-aged girl.
而且 她总是用同样的措辞
And, she always posted the same verbiage.
那什么 "这不是色情
Something like, "This is not porn.
我的兴趣在挠痒痒上"
My interest is in tickling."
她说她是个挠痒痒的狂热爱好者 而且
And she just said that she was a tickling fanatic and...
我是说 那些帖子到处都是
But, I mean, these posts were everywhere.
然后 就跳出了一些视频
And then, um, some videos started popping up,
你知道 就是 完全无意中的
you know, very, you know, innocent.
那些应该就是我最早在网络上看到的
And, those are probably the first
挠痒痒的视频了
tickle videos that I ever saw on the Internet.
90年代中期后
There are still traces of Terri tickle online
在网上仍然有特里 挠痒的踪迹
from the mid-'90s,
就像理查德说的 她沉溺于挠痒痒
and as Richard said, she was tickle-obsessed.
就像简一样 她也会雇人
Like Jane, she also hired other people
拍她想要的视频
to shoot the videos she wanted.
嗯 不过就是奇怪的富家女孩
Well, the, uh, just strange, rich brat,
我猜你会这么说
I guess you could say.
看男人们被绑起来 被挠痒
Someone who, uh, got her rocks off by, uh,
来释放压力的什么家伙
seeing guys, uh, tied and tickled.
很显然是一个极端的女性施虐狂
Obviously an extreme dominatrix.
在他一生中的大部分时光
For most of his life,
戴夫 斯塔尔几乎都在
Dave starr has worked on the edges
娱乐业的边沿工作
of the entertainment industry,
甚至参演几部色情电影
even acting in a couple of pornos.
在90年代中期
During the mid-'90s,
他注意到特里在网上发帖 求挠痒痒的视频
he noticed Terri's online posts wanting tickling videos...
要很多
Lots of them.
特里当时在寻找18到23岁的年轻男子
Terri was, uh, out there looking for guys, uh, 18 to 23.
而我 觉得这个
And I, uh, figured that it would, um...
鉴于我有选角的工作经验
Be something right up my alley,
这正中我下怀
based on my, uh, working in casting.
她到底招募别人去做什么呢
What sort of things was she recruiting for specifically?
啊 痒痒折磨电影 痒痒折磨视频
Uh, tickle torture films. Tickle torture videos.
你能把那个东西转过来让我看得到吗
Can you turn that thing around so I can see it?
好的
All right.
-这样行吗 -嗯 可以
- Is that all right? - Yeah, that's good.
她声称是为了私人收藏
She claimed it was for a private collection,
我就在想 "好吧 业余制作"
so I was thinking, "Okay, amateur hour."
不过就我而言 我很快把它扩展到专业的水平上
But me, I rapidly took it into a professional level.
好吧 你是挠痒痒爱好者吗
Okay, are you, uh, ticklish?
嗯 是啊
Uh, yes, I am.
很好 向前走一步
Okay, step forward about a foot.
很好 把你的双手放在脑后 双手十指交叉
Okay. Place your hands behind your head, inter-clasp them.
不过 再向后退一点
Step back a little further, though.
很好 在那儿就好
Okay, right about there.
很好 十指交叉
Okay, inter-clasp them
在这整个挠痒测试的过程中
and do not release them at any time
任何时候都不要放开
during the entire tickle test.
给这家伙上最厉害的
Do your worst on this one.
我们会让他们经过
We would put them in through
第一阶段的海选
their stage one audition,
也就是提问和测试挠痒
which is the questions and the test tickles.
不要歪倒 一直看向我们
Do not collapse. Stay looking up at us.
一直面对着我们
Stay facing us.
第二阶段是把他们绑到桌上 挠他们痒痒
Stage two is tying them to the table, tickling them,
每十五分钟翻一次身
flipping them over every 15 minutes,
就跟烤肠烤肉翻个儿似的
kind of like a sausage or meat.
在那之后 呃
And then after that, uh,
在那时我们开始了挠痒竞赛
we had the competitive tickling at that point.
挠痒大战之类的事情
Tickle wars and stuff like that.
那就是批量制作了
And that would involve a massive production.
好的 别笑了
Okay, don't laugh.
你已经忍不住咯咯笑了 是不是
You're giggling already, aren't you?
那么 你可能就是 大卫 斯塔尔
Well, you just might be the type of person
正在找的那类人
that David starr is looking for.
他是好莱坞的制片人
He is a Hollywood producer
正在制作一款基于现实的真人游戏节目
working on a new reality-based game show
名叫 挠一挠聊一聊
called tickle talk.
它可能比
It might be preferable to
《幸存者》[CBS王牌真人秀 目前已经播出三十多季] 里生吃老鼠吃蛆要好受一点
eating rats or grubs on survivor
可也好不了多少
but just barely.
我是安妮 詹姆斯 K96新闻电台
I'm Anne James, ksen k96 news.
戴夫[大卫的昵称] 斯塔尔五年都持续有活
Dave starr had steady work for five years,
哪怕在特里住院的六个月期间
even when Terri was hospitalized for six months.
那段时间里
During that time,
她给我写信详细说明
she just wrote letters specifying
她想要在挠痒录像里的内容
exactly what she wanted in the tickling videos.
大卫 圣诞快乐
"David, merry Christmas!
太抱歉了 我因为单核白血球增多症（一种传染性病症 部分症状和流感相似）正在住院
So sorry, I'm in the hospital with mono."
大卫 我只需要你做这几件事
"David, just a few things I need you to do..."
告诉他们 我病一好马上把电脑送过去
"Tell them I will send the computer as soon as I'm well."
他叫乔希 我希望在二月就又能够上网了
"His name is Josh." "I hope to be online again in feb."
我还在病床上 没有其他事了 特里
"I'm still sick in bed." "That's all for now. Td."
我最怕痒的地方 我猜是
My most ticklish place is, I guess...
一定是 我的腿
Definitely, like... It'd have to be in my legs...
比我的胳肢窝 和脚心还怕痒 我想
More than, like, my armpits or my feet, I think, but...
那时候她想建一个网站
At that time she wanted to put up
并且真的建了网站有一段时间
and did indeed put up a website for a while, uh,
未经允许就发布那些视频
unauthorized releasing of the videos...
不顾参与者的意愿
Against the agreement of the talent,
然后我也翻脸了
and I flipped my lid.
想当然啦
And, lo and behold,
她开始用他们的名字注册这些域名
she goes and registers domains in their names
然后开始
and then proceeds to...
把这些视频发布在这些网站上
Release all their content on to those particular websites.
她就给我发邮件 大概说
She was, like, sending me emails about, um,
你觉得你妈妈
"What do you think your mother's
对此会怎么看
gonna think about this?"
然后 我就回说 去你妈的贱人
And then, like, I'd be like, you know, "Fuck you, bitch."
然后她就开始跟我对着干
And she'd be, like... Like, totally antagonizing.
我想说 她就是个贱屄
Like... I mean, she was such a cunt.
她不只侮辱我还侮辱我的家人 你知道吗
It was an assault not just on me but on my family, you know?
你瞧 我的家庭是再保守不过了
I mean, I couldn't have a more conservative family, you know?
我家人都是共和党人 从军的
I'm, I'm in a family full of republican, military people,
而我又是 我曾是个专业的银行家
and I'm a... I was a professional banker.
而现在 我在一个跟色情网站差不多的网页上面
And here I am, like, with basically a porn site,
尽管我不是赤身裸体 但是 也没什么区别
where I'm not naked, but, I mean, I might as well be.
你看 这简直毁了我的人生
You know, this was ruining my life at the time.
我当时是这样感觉的
That's how I felt.
这无疑影响了我的生活
It certainly was affecting my ability to function,
因为这太折磨人了
because it was so emotionally draining.
还有部分原因是因为没有人帮我
Part of the reason was because there's nobody to help me.
就好像你对你的人生无能为力
It's like you lose control over, you know, your life.
嗯 就是那时 事情开始变得糟糕
Well, that's when the, uh, crap started happening,
对我来说
uh, with me.
额 我觉得 那好 因为是我
Um, you decide, "Okay, because I, uh,
为她招来这些受害者
I closed down submissions for her,
那我
and,
我想 我基本上就是她的痒贩子
I guess, I basically was like her tickling drug dealer,
既然 她再也得不到她的痒了
and, uh, since she wasn't getting her drug any more,
她开始痒病发作了
she was going through tickle withdrawals.
发生了什么
And what happened?
我开始收到
I started, uh, receiving the, uh,
奇怪的明信片 奇怪的信息
strange postcards, and the, uh, strange messages.
挠痒参与者开始收到信息
The, uh... the, uh, talent was starting to receive messages.
她还用一种电话骚扰的东西
And, uh, she also deployed a thing called the phone blaster,
就是给每个人打电话 一些恶心的内容
which was to call everybody with obscene messages.
这个人真是嗑嗨了
This person's on drugs.
这个人肯定是溜冰还是什么
This person's gotta be on crystal or something,
往菊花里塞可卡因 类似的行为
or taking cocaine up the ass, or something like that.
太奇怪了
It was weird.
我很乐意给你看这些
I'm glad to be able to make this available to you.
大卫保留了一些特里发给他的信
David kept a number of letters Terri had sent him
并很愿意给我看看它们的扰人程度
and was keen to show me the extent of the abuse.
-好了 -就是这些神奇的东西
- All right. - This is the magic stuff.
好的 这里都有什么
All right, what have we got?
嗯 基本上是一些
Yeah. Uh, these are basically copies
她网上言论的打印件
of what she would post online.
芭芭拉是谁 是你的
So who's Barbara? Is that your...?
是我母亲
That's my mother.
多毛又饥渴 多毛又饥渴
"Hairy and horny. Hairy and horny.
怕痒的犹太摄像师 大卫 斯塔尔
Jewish tickle filmer David w. Starr
鹰钩鼻 多毛又饥渴
is hook-nosed, hairy and horny."
就这几句话 她翻来覆去地讲
She's used that tagline for many, many, many times.
那你
What did your...?
当这些信件出现
What did your mother think of this stuff
你母亲是怎么看的
when this turned up? I mean...
事实上 她的原话是
Actually, her phrase was, uh...
这里有个她留给我的便签
Here's a, uh, note that she left me because, uh,
她会在信箱给我留着这些
she would hold these for me in the mail
仅仅是说 又来个一件脏东西
and basically just say, "Here's another nasty thing."
这有一封根本没打开过
And that one actually is unopened.
到现在我都没打开过
I've never even opened it to this date.
让我们看看这个想象力丰富的小朋友都说了什么
And let's see what our little illustrious friend had to say.
哦 天 还是张卡片
Oh, god. So it's a card.
玫瑰是红的 紫罗兰是兰的
"Roses are red, violets are bue."
蓝字都不会写
Can't spell worth shit.
大卫 w 斯塔尔是罪恶之源
"David w. Starr has brought this upon you.
可能你希望 不是爱德华
Perhaps you wish, perhaps instead,
而是大卫你的废物儿子 在九泉
that David your failure, not Edward, were dead."
这是说我的哥哥 他已经死了
That's a reference to my brother, who is dead.
这也太极端了 有点神经质
That's, uh, really extreme. A little bit psycho.
那么 我想 当你收到这些内容
But, I mean, what...? When you were getting all this material
有些还在玷污你
and some of it's talking about your brother who
已经去世的兄弟 -嗯嗯
- has passed away and... - Uh-huh.
给你妈妈写信
Writing this stuff to your mother,
我想说 这一定
I mean, that, that must have...
我是说 每周都收到这些可不太好过
I mean, that... that's not nice receiving that on weekly basis.
的确不好过 而且是每周都有
Uh, no, but it was on a weekly basis, uh, yeah.
他们哪来的这些闲工夫
Yeah, where did they have the time?
-天 是张生日卡 -嗯
- Jeez, it's a birthday card. - Yeah.
生日快乐
"Happy birthday.
死去的爱德华 斯塔尔 这也太残忍了不是
Edward starr dead." This is really cruel, right?
简直是病态的
It's very sick.
我关于特里 狄思拓打听到越多
The more I hear about Terri disisto,
她听上去越像简 奥布莱恩
the more she sounds like Jane o'brien.
很明显的 她俩都很喜欢挠痒痒
To state the obvious, they both really enjoy tickling.
她们还喜欢掌控和发飙
They also like being in control and lashing out.
太感谢了 保持联系
I really appreciate it and stay in touch.
而且原来特里的嗜好追溯到
And it turns out Terri's habits started
戴夫 斯塔尔参与的很久之前
way before Dave starr got involved.
我找到一个记者 在九十年代他曾经花了一年探索
I've found a journalist who'd spent a year uncovering
关于特里 狄思拓的真相
the truth about Terri disisto during the '90s.
特里 狄思拓的做法是用这些男孩
Terri disisto's mo was to bait these boys
渴望的东西
into making tickling videos with
诱惑他们来拍挠痒视频 是这样吗
things that they wanted, right?
你看 想象一个十几岁的少年
You know, I mean, imagine being a teenage boy,
收到一个莫名其妙的邮件说
and, like, you get this random email saying, you know,
我看到你发的关于这个演唱会的状态 那么
"I saw your posting about the phish concert, and, uh,
你要不要去
how would you like to go?"
或是说 我可以给你一千块现金
Or, " I can send you $1000 cash."
你住在詹姆斯麦迪逊大学[位于弗吉尼亚州的公立大学]的宿舍
And you're like... You're living in your dorm
你会说 行 当然啦
at James Madison university. You're like, "Yeah, sure.
你会给我一千块 才怪
You're gonna send me $1000 cash. Right."
快递第二天就送到你宿舍门口
Fedex pulls up in front of your dorm the next day,
十张百元钞票
and there is ten $100 bills.
不劳而获
You haven't done anything.
他们想要什么她就送什么
She would just keep sending them whatever they wanted,
你知道的 电脑 相机 现金
you know. Computers, cameras, more cash,
摇滚演唱会门票
tickets to rock concerts.
不过到了一个阶段 就算一个少年
Then at some point, even a teenage boy
也有愿望都被满足的时刻
has all the toys that they want.
他们会说 我不干了
And they say, "I... I'm done."
我认为她最憎恨的事情就是被拒绝
But I think the thing that she hates the most was no.
就好像引爆了一个炸弹
It was like... A bomb went off.
她会说 那好
And she'd say, "Well,
你要是不干了 我叫你吃不了兜着走
if you don't do it, I'm gonna make your life hell."
我会把这些视频
"I'm gonna send clips of these videos
发给你的摔跤教练
to your wrestling coach."
我会把这些视频发给你妈妈
"I'm gonna send clips of these videos to your mom."
发给你奶奶
"I'm gonna send clips of these videos to your grandmother."
发给你的
"I'm gonna send clips of these videos
大学校长
to the president of your university."
发到整个网络上
"I'm gonna post them all over the Internet."
我会假扮成你 在网上胡作非为
"I'm gonna pretend to be you and do things on the Internet
把你的名声搞臭
that are gonna create a terrible reputation for you."
我会把你们整个学校的电脑系统搞掉
"I'm gonna shut down the entire college campus computer system
让他们认为是你做的
at your college, and they're gonna think it's you."
她真的这么做了
And then it happened.
我做的第一个报道就是关于
The first story I did was because
她攻击了德雷克塞尔大学
she was attacking, um, drexel university.
我发现有一个学生
And I found the student who, um,
为她拍了几个视频
had made a number of videos for her.
当他去费城上大学
And when he came to Philadelphia to go to college,
她还想让他继续拍这些视频
she wanted him to continue making these videos,
而他想要和她断绝来往
and he wanted to cut off his relationship with her.
她开始全方面地报复
And she retaliated on so many levels.
他们学校邮箱服务器的主机被关掉
Their email servers' computers were being shut down
来阻止
with these denial-of-service attacks
显示是来自这个学生的联机攻击
that indicated that they were coming from him.
用他的名字
Email-bombing the white house,
向白宫群发垃圾邮件
indicating that it came from him.
当你才十九岁 特勤处出现在
Yeah, that's pretty serious stuff when the secret service
你的宿舍门口还是很严重的
shows up in your college dorm and you're 19 years old.
我只是觉得好奇 就想办法
I was just curious, and I somehow
在美国在线上联系到她
started contacting Terri on aol.
她有个账号
She had an account.
我们会在深夜聊天
And we would have these chats late at night.
我很好奇这个大名鼎鼎的网络人物脑子里
And I was curious what kind of mind was behind this...
都想着些什么
Celebrated Internet personage.
是些疯狂的想法
And it was, it was kind of crazy.
我们这样聊着
We would have these conversations,
她会
and she would...
当她意识到我喝了葡萄酒 她会说
When she realized that I did wine, she would say,
哦 我在喝一杯霞多丽哪
"Oh, I'm having a glass of chardonnay!"
我完全能想象到她的声音 当它在我脑袋里回荡
And I could just hear this voice because as it went on,
就好像她完全沉醉在
it was almost like she was completely intoxicated
她拥有的对他人
with this power that she had to...
极具破坏性的能力
To be so destructive against people.
我听说有个孩子拒绝继续拍这种视频
I got word about a kid who refused to make the videos.
他在网上求助
He posted that he needed some help,
有人说能够帮忙
and somebody said they would help him.
不知怎的他邮件收到一个文档
And somehow he got emailed a file,
并被告知 你把这个压缩文档发给特里
and he was told, "If you email this zip file to Terri,
她就不会再打搅你了
she will leave you alone."
然后 他把压缩文件发给我了
And then he sent me that zip file.
你知道 我还记得打开它之后在想
You know, and I remember opening it up and thinking...
"哇 就是这个了 这是
"Wow! You know, this is it. Like, this is...
这是确凿的证据"
This is the smoking gun."
这个压缩文件包括她硬盘里的文档
The zip file contained documents from her hard drive.
如我所料 有关于挠痒的视频文件
As expected, there were files relating to tickling shoots.
但它们同时也揭露了特里 挠痒的真身
But they also revealed the true identity of Terri tickle.
大卫 迪马托
David d'amato.
她其实是个他 对吗
She is really he, right?
他是一所高中的副校长
He was an assistant principal in a high school?
我就是
I just...
没法相信这一点
Couldn't believe it.
我不知道为什么 但这些看上去
I don't know why, but it just seemed...
这就是那个利用这些年轻人的那个虐待狂
Here is this sadistic person exploiting these young people,
通常还是些未成年人
often underage,
让他们的生活狼狈 让他们难堪
making their lives miserable, embarrassing them,
到了如此地步的家伙
to an extent that it's every...
这与一名教育者所应做的所有事情都背道而驰
It goes against everything that an educator should be doing.
当我做了一些调查 我发现
When I did some more checking, I found out that
他大概在十年内任职过八所学校
he had worked at, like, eight schools in ten years.
这对我来说总是个警示
Which to me was always a red flag
一定有什么不对劲
that there was something else going on.
我的意思是 这可不仅仅是单纯的不称职了
I mean, that's more than just sheer incompetence.
然后我找到了她的社会保险号码
And then I found social security numbers for her
发现他犯下了欺诈
that he had gotten fraudulently...
因为冒用了亡者的名字
With dead people's names.
所以我联系了联邦调查局
So I contacted the FBI.
把我所知的一切都告诉了他们
I turned over all my information to them.
一周之内 他就被逮捕了
Within a week, they busted him.
我们对判决结果感到震惊
We were shocked at the sentencing
因为他如此轻易地脱身了
because he got off so easy.
对造成了如此多伤害的人来说
For somebody who had done so much damage,
这个结果真是出乎我的意料
to me it was just extraordinary.
甚至还不在这些发生之后
And to not, to not have restrictions on their
限制他们对互联网的访问 怎么回事
Internet access after that, how could...?
还有 对了 他还还去法学院读书
And the... oh! And the idea that he was going to law school
真是荒唐可笑
was just absurd.
事实是大卫 迪马托的父亲 乔治
It turns out David d'amato's father, George,
联合创办了华尔街最大的法律公司之一 迪马托和林奇
co-founded one of wall street's biggest law firms,
大卫得到了一名很优秀的辩护律师
d'amato & lynch, and David got a really great lawyer.
迪马托被允许于父亲的母校 福特汉姆大学 学习法律
Instead of prison, d'amato was allowed to serve his sentence
同时在中途康复站[社区机构]服刑
in the halfway house while he studied law
而不是在监狱里
at his father's Alma mater, Fordham university.
法官不知什么原因
The judge, for some reason,
下决心认可这条法学院的途径
decided that he would endorse the law school path, right?
因为 他就是块
Because, like, this is exactly the kind of person
做律师的料 对不对
that should be a lawyer, right?
欺诈他人
Somebody who has defrauded people,
窃取身份
somebody who has stolen people's identities.
这可是联邦重罪 对吗
A federal freakin' crime, right?
我想说的是 比如窃取身份
I mean... like, you know, stolen identity.
盗用一个死去妇女的社保账号
Stolen a social security number of a dead woman,
是两个死人 对吗
of two dead people, right?
上面说 “大卫 迪马托 39岁 住在花园城市
It said, "David d'amato, 39, of garden city,
对两件计算机诈骗和滥用计算机的联邦案件
plead guilty for two federal counts of
做出认罪”
computer fraud and abuse."
对挠痒只字不提
Nothing about the tickling,
对男孩们只字不提 对身份窃取只字不提
nothing about the boys, nothing about the identity theft.
只字不提
Zero. Nothing.
福特汉姆大学一知道迪马托的定罪结果
Once Fordham became aware of d'amato's convictions,
就取消了他的入学资格
his admission was revoked.
无法继续学习法律的迪马托
No longer able to study law,
在监狱里完成了刑期
d'amato finished his sentence in prison.
但我意识到 这并没有阻止他的挠痒大计
But I've realized that didn't stop the tickling.
这是2002年 这是写给大卫 斯塔尔的信
So, this is 2002. So this is writing to David starr,
大卫拍摄这些男孩挠痒痒的过程
who would shoot these boys tickling
然后把视频发送
and then send the videos...
给特里 那是
To Terri. That was a, that's--
因为她想要的是
because she, what she would have is...
-你需要眼镜吗 -早些时候
- Do you want your glasses? - Back in the early days...
好的 早些时候
Yeah. Back in the early days...
特里会让朋友们挠他们的痒 然后发给他们
Terri would have friends tickle them and send them the...
那都是业余的录像带
They were amateur tapes.
-现在变成专业级的了吗 -这就是
- These are now professional? - Well, this is...
-看看上面的日期 -2002年
- Look at the date on it. - '02?
看看日期
Look at the date.
-“T”指的是特里吗 -对 这是特里的字
- Is the "T" Terri? - Yeah, it's Terri writing.
所以那大概还是 他还被关在监狱里的时候
So that was during, um, lock-up time.
哦 在监狱 我知道了
Oh, in jail. I get it.
“大卫 还有几件事情 邮件 解释我的病情”
"David, a few other things. Email... explain my illness."
“告诉他一旦我的单核白血球增多症好转
Oh. "Tell him I'll pay everything owed
我就会把所有欠款还清”
as soon as the mono is better."
“来张头部特写” 天呐
Oh. "Get headshots." My god! Oh, my god!
“我病得厉害 所以有段时间不会上网”
"I won't be online for a while as I am very sick." Oh.
-停不下来吧 -当然
- Couldn't stop. - No. No.
似乎自从上世纪90年代中期开始
It seems that since the mid-'90s,
大卫 迪马托就没停止各种花招
David d'amato has never stopped finding elaborate ways
让年轻人来挠痒痒
to get young men to tickle each other.
他那特里 蒂克尔的伪装
His persona of Terri tickle
似乎在2006年左右就销声匿迹了
seems to have dropped off the radar around 2006.
过了一段时间 简 奥布莱恩登上了舞台
A while later, Jane o'brien arrived on the scene.
我们把这个推论放到了网上
We've posted this theory online,
大卫 迪马托不太高兴
and David d'amato is not happy.
他雇了不止一个 而是两个私家侦探
He's hired not one, but two private investigators,
一个在新西兰 一个在纽约
one in New Zealand and one in New York.
用意很明确 他们让我们停下手头正在做的事情
The message is clear. They tell us to stop what we're doing
并暗示迪马托与简 奥布莱恩媒体毫无关联
and that d'amato has nothing to do with Jane o'brien media.
最绝的是
On top of that,
大卫 迪马托也雇了一名新西兰的律师
David d'amato has also hired a New Zealand lawyer.
他要求道歉并撤回相关报道
He's demanding an apology and retraction
否则新西兰法庭上见
or else he'll see us in a New Zealand court.
我们现在遭受两面夹击
We're now being attacked
一边是简 奥布莱恩的律师
by Jane o'brien's lawyers on one side
另一边是大卫 迪马托的律师
and David d'amato's on the other,
双方都坚称他们彼此毫无关系
both insisting they have nothing to do with each other.
我们又一次地不知所措了
Once again, we're way out of our depth.
当一通密歇根的电话打来
Things get even more surreal
事情变得更加离奇了
with a phone call from Michigan,
又有一个简组织起来的
where there's a very different tickling operation
很不一样的挠痒痒行动
also being run by Jane.
所以说 在这个地方
So, like, crime is pretty high--
犯罪率非常高 对吗
Yeah-- - ...Here, right?
谋杀 抢劫 强奸 还有盗窃
Murder, robberies, um, rape, I mean, theft.
这里全都有
It's all up there,
特别是考虑到 这个地方并不大
especially for being as small, um, as what it is.
现在 我们获得了
We've made it now, uh,
全美最危险的100个城市之一的称号
on to the top 100 most dangerous cities in the United States.
你觉不觉得 从某种意义上说
Do you think on some level
简是因为这个地方的贫穷才在这里拍摄的
Jane kind of directed things here because it is a poor area?
对啊 你知道贫困
Yeah, you know, the poverty level, you know,
-让人失去理智 -嗯
- is easy to target, you know. - Mm.
对小孩子来说 成千上万美元
Thousands of dollars in kids' hands is...
那可是一笔不小的数目
That's a, that's a big, big deal.
简看中了一项
Jane has taken a liking to one
马斯基根市的主要运动 综合格斗
of muskegon's main sports, mixed martial arts.
一群年轻 健硕的人极度渴望外快
A group of young, athletic men desperate for extra money.
所以简努力想要突破进这个综合格斗的领域
That's what she was trying to do, is break into the mma world.
因为在综合格斗中 为了避免被制服
Because it's not illegal to tickle somebody
去挠对方的痒痒 并不算犯规
to get out of a submission in mixed martial arts.
她试图去利用这一点
Like, she was trying to pitch that
因为
because she, like,
她查阅了所有规则和相关资料
looked it up in all the rules and everything.
不过你在比赛中途通过挠痒痒
But if you tickle a guy in the middle of that ring
使对手屈服
to get out of a submission,
你走出擂台观众都会给你一巴掌
you might step out of the cage and get punched in the face.
就像是 再过个几千年我格斗都不会
Like, never in a million years out of all my fights
去挠痒痒
would I ever try to tickle somebody
来获胜 绝不可能
to get out of a submission. Fuck, no!
作为一名前搏击手
As an ex-fighter,
乔丹受雇在镇子里招募挠痒人才
Jordan was paid to recruit tickling talent in the town.
他是唯一一个愿意上镜的马斯基根人
He's the only one in muskegon prepared to appear on camera.
她给一个我找的人开价 一辆2014款雪佛兰科鲁兹和三万美元
She offered my one buddy a 2014 Chevy cruze and $30,000.
-为什么 去挠痒吗 -对啊
- What? What for? To tickle? - Yeah.
只是因为 她喜欢他
Just 'cause, like, she liked him.
没错 他曾是她的最爱
Yeah, right. She... He was a favorite.
-就像 对 -对
- Like, yeah. - Yeah.
亚洲人和红毛都是他们口中的优质人选
Asians and redheads are what they call premiums.
如果你找到了 她会给你奖金
If you get those, like, she gives you bonuses.
我是乔丹 史基拉斯 这里是CET活动
I'm Jordan schillaci, and this is cet.
今天 我们即将进行一次讨论而非辩论
Uh, we're gonna be having a discussion,
关于是否在搏斗的情况中
more of a debate today about whether tickling
挠痒是有效的
is effective in a combat situation.
我们最后还建了个挠痒室 就是
We ended up setting up a tickle cell. Like,
你把找到的人带进去
where you get guys to come in,
“我们给你酬金 你付钱让他们面试”
"We'll pay you and you pay them to audition."
别
No!
所以我们会挑个旅社 普普通通的
So we'd choose a hotel, nothing fancy,
人们会走来走去 到处乱逛
and, uh, the guys would come in and hang out, you know,
抽烟 喝酒 吃披萨 上床
smoke, drink, eat pizza, fuckin', and we'd hurry up
我们就赶快把五到七个受试者过一遍
and run through, you know, five, six, seven guys.
所以说 你就负责马斯基根市的挠痒室吗
So you're... you were looking after the tickle cell in muskegon?
对 他们遍布全美
Yeah, they have them set up all over the us.
俄亥俄 密歇根 佛罗里达 纽约
Ohio, Michigan, Florida, New York.
-他们无处不在 -确实
- I mean, they're everywhere. - Right.
-他们都是简旗下的吗 -对
- And they're all for Jane? - Yeah.
真是可怕
Fuckin' hell.
就是那里 许多人开始
Well, that's where a lot of people started
变得非常非常焦虑
getting really really upset, man.
因为冷不防地
Because all of sudden these videos
这些本来只是面试的视频出现在油管
that are supposed to be just auditions were on YouTube,
Vimeo 还有所有你能想到的网站
vimeo, and every other site you could imagine.
-的确是这样 -没人会一笑而过
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Nobody was okay with that.
有一个人 叫布罗迪
One of the guys, Brodie,
他的家庭对此非常烦恼 视频到处都是
like, his family was very upset with him. It was all over.
人们对他都不断地指指点点
Like, people just picked on him and picked on him.
他还是未成年人 还在上学
You know, he was underage, still in school.
这件事不应该泄露到互联网上
And it wasn't supposed to go out on the Internet.
就根本不应该发上去
It wasn't supposed to be put up, and, uh,
真的是糟糕透顶
you know, that just kind of sucked.
像我说过的那样 它让布罗迪
Because, like I said, it took Brodie...
它给了致命一击
It hit one of the hardest.
先是这整个突然的情况
Like, this whole situation
然后又是未成年 又是他的父母
and then being underage and his parents.
你要去向谁求助 你要去攻击谁
Who do you have to turn to? Who are you going to attack?
没人 简 奥布莱恩是一个幽灵 没人知道它的真实身份
No... Jane o'brien's a ghost. Nobody knows who it is.
小科迪 别
Cody-bear, no.
这是科尔顿 我的外甥
This is Colton, this is my nephew.
-嘿 小伙子 -科尔顿 你多大了
- Hey, man. - Colton, how old are you?
你多大了
How old are you?
-三岁 -三岁啦
- Three. - You're three?
真三岁吗 好吧
You're three? All right.
-我是大卫 -我是菲尔 你好
- I'm David. - I'm Phil. How are you doing?
很高兴见到你 先生
It's nice to meet you, sir.
当乔丹开始谈论这件事情
I was really, really reluctant
我心里一百个不愿意
when Jordan started talking about this.
他说 “妈妈 这个女人看上去正直而守法”
And he's like, "This lady seems straight and legit, mom."
我就说 “这些男孩还年轻”
I'm like, you know, "These... these boys are young."
太轻易就相信 不过当你年岁渐长
It's easy to believe, but when you're an old mom,
你就对男孩子们多了个心眼
you're a little more leery for the boys, and,
我一开始就察觉到不对
I was very leery right from get-go
孩子们会麻烦缠身
that the boys were gonna get into trouble
这根本不正当
and this was not legit.
她像是富可敌国
She has all the money in the world, it seems like,
无论是谁 她有可以满足
whoever it is, to be able to do this.
不过他们等到你开始依赖
But they're waiting for that day that you rely
将其作为最后的救命稻草
on that as a sole income.
那才是她至高的权利之旅
That was her big, I think, power trip.
她等到我们都依靠那份收入
She waited until a bunch of us relied on that income
因为那是我们唯一的生财之道
because that was our only source of income.
我们深陷其中 我们不想
We'd been doing it for so long, we didn't think...
等到她有绝对的控制权
She waited until she had complete control,
基本上 你到那种地步
basically, over your situation,
她就会开始
and that's when she wanted to yank that rug
釜底抽薪
right out from under you.
大卫 迪马托 你听说过这个名字吗
David d'amato. Have you heard that name before?
和这些有关系吗
In relation to all this stuff?
就是字面上你意思 颤抖了
I am literally, like, trembling right now.
你真的在发抖吗
Are you actually shaking?
是啊 我实际上 就在 颤抖 我没
Yeah, I'm actually, like, shaking. Like, I'm not, like...
就像我说的 从这里起 我都没在乎
Like I said, like, from being from here, I don't take shit.
就像 要是我遇到这家伙 一定会给他当头一击
Like, if I met up with that guy, I'd punch him right out.
等他醒来 会发现被绑在椅子上
And when he woke up, he'd be strapped to a chair with a...
我就像这样
Like, I'd be like,
兄弟 现在一切老实交待
"Dude, you're telling me everything right now."
在这城镇上挠痒痒还在继续
The tickling's still happening in this town.
这钱仿佛源源不竭
The money is endless.
它永不止歇地流入
I've never seen it stop coming and just flowing in.
不仅仅在密歇根 洛杉矶
And it's not just through Michigan and la,
它无处不在
it's everywhere.
比如 英格兰 澳大利亚 意大利
Like, england, Australia, Italy.
钱一直都来来去去
I mean, the money's still coming and going.
这个挠痒帝国
This tickling empire
远比我们想象的要庞大
is way bigger than we ever imagined.
我们要去纽约寻找大卫 迪马托
We're going to New York to find David d'amato.
我都能闻到那富得流油的味道
I can feel the rich/bad aura.
大卫 迪马托的地址位于花园城市
David d'amato's address is listed in garden city,
长岛的富人区
an affluent suburb of long island.
他住在那栋楼的顶层
He lives on the top floor of this building.
这里是兰斯 罗伯特
Lance Roberts speaking.
噢 你好 我是大卫
Oh, hi. It's David speaking.
我想跟大卫 迪马托聊一聊
I just wanted to talk to David d'amato.
额 知道了 我不能给你他的号码
Um, okay. I can't give you his phone number.
我真的不能提供任何
I really can't even give you any
他的私人信息
personal information on him.
好吧
Okay.
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
-是的 我认识 -你是他的朋友吗
- Yes, I do. Yes. - You're a friend of his?
额 我不是他的朋友 不是 不过 我
Um, I'm not a friend, no, but I've, um...
我一直尝试联系他
I've been trying to get in touch with him
一直都无果
but have been struggling.
好的 我能做的就是
Okay, what I do is,
给他捎个口信
I have a way of leaving him a message.
我不能保证如果他都不认识你
I can't guarantee that he's gonna call you back
还会回电
if he doesn't know you.
-好的 非常感谢你 -不客气
- Okay, thank you so much. Bye. - You're welcome.
迪马托 从未回电
D'amato never calls us back,
我们也没有别的直接联系方式
and we've got no other way to contact him directly.
如此苦恼
So annoying.
没关系 还有明天呢
It's all right. There's still tomorrow.
不过当晚我们接到了个让人沮丧的电话
But that night we get a frustrating phone call.
我的忧虑是在我们之后的行程中
My concern is that we can't do more or less anything
完全束手无策了
we have planned for the rest of the trip.
我知道 只是 都快发疯了
I know. It's, like, it's fuckin' insane.
好的 拜拜
Okay. Bye-bye.
所有威胁都让我们电影制片人焦虑
All the threats are worrying our film's producer.
他不想让我们冒险激起
He doesn't want us to risk provoking
迪马托进一步的法律行动
any further legal action from d'amato.
所以他说
So he's saying,
你们可不可以不要追着迪马托跑
"Well, what if you do everything that you were gonna do,
其他怎么弄都行
except don't go and chase d'amato down?"
我就说 我们所做的一切
And I'm like, "Well, anything we do
都会让迪马托知道
that lets d'amato know we're looking into him again."
-嗯 现在起就是这样 -嗯 就是这样
- Well, from now on in is that. - Yeah, literally.
所以他说 嗯 要不我们直接一点
So he says, "Well, maybe we cut the thing short, then.
你们回来吧
Just go home."
我知道 简直是疯了一样
I know it's like... It's fuckin' insane.
第二天我们就抓了迪马托个正着
The next day we put chasing d'amato on hold.
我很好奇到底
I want to know how on earth
一个前副校长哪来这么多钱
a former deputy principal pays for all this.
我们找不到任何他从这些视频中获利的迹象
We can't find any sign he's earning money from the videos,
反倒是他斥巨资拍这些视频
but he's spending lots of money making them.
每个月送多达十个人从世界各地
He's flying up to ten people into la almost every month
飞去洛杉矶
from all over the world,
安排到挺好的酒店
putting them up in a nice hotel,
给他们上千的现金
paying them thousands in cash.
这还没算上
And that's not even taking into account
像在马斯基根
the cost of running tickle cells,
维持挠痒室的开销
like the one in muskegon.
大卫的双亲都已去世
Both David's parents are now deceased,
不过他父亲留下华尔街最大的法律事务所
but his father's law firm is one of wall street's biggest.
可能大卫也受益于
Maybe David is reaping the benefits
他父亲留下的帝国
of his father's empire.
迪马托和林奇
D'amato & lynch.
噢 嗨 我想问一下 额
Oh, hi. I just had an inquiry, um,
大卫 迪马托 嗯
about the relationship with, uh, um,
和公司的关系 就是那个乔治 迪马托的儿子
David d'amato with the company, the son of George d'amato.
我还能向谁咨询
Is there someone I could talk to about this?
无可奉告 很抱歉 迪马托先生已经去世很久了
No, I'm sorry. And Mr. D'amato has been gone for a long time.
是 是 我在调查他的儿子 大卫
Yeah, yeah. I'm looking into the background to his son, David.
我只是想知道他是否
And I'm just trying to figure out whether he's got
还和公司有经济关系
any financial relationship with the company still.
我 我确实不知道 抱歉 爱莫能助
No, I... I really don't know. I'm sorry, I can't help you.
公司里面我还能问谁这个问题吗
Is there someone I could talk to at d'amato & lynch to find out?
额 我觉得没有 抱歉
Mm. Not that I believe, no. I'm sorry.
好的 不过总有方法查明 绝对的
Okay, but there must be a way to find out, surely?
-额 至少这里没有 谢谢你
- Um, not here. Thank you.
我几年都没见到大卫了
I haven't seen David in quite a few years.
我对他一无所知
I have no knowledge of him now.
我几年都没跟他联系过了
Not in many years have I had any contact with him,
所以我什么消息都无法提供
so I really couldn't give you any information.
是 他一直都很针对我
Yeah, he's been pretty aggressive towards me,
我只是想知道他的动机
so I'm just trying to figure out what his motivations are--
离他远点 我只能说这么多
Get away from him, that's all I can tell you.
是吗 -对 离他远点
Really? - Yeah. Stay away from him.
这就是我和每一个
This was every conversation I had
与大卫 迪马托相关的人士的聊天缩影
with anyone even remotely related to David d'amato.
我无可奉告 劝你不要插手
"I can't tell you anything, but stay away."
不过我所做的恰恰相反
But all I want to do is the opposite.
总有人要正视这些欺凌 诉讼
Someone has to confront this bully, lawsuits or not.
好了 这辆车是我们的目标
Okay. So, this is the car we're looking for.
梅赛德斯 奔驰 ML430
It's a Mercedes benz ml430.
大卫 迪马托肯定另寻他路避开我们
David d'amato has gone out of his way to avoid us.
我们猜想要是在他公寓门口等得足够久
We figure if we wait outside his apartment long enough,
他终究会出来的
eventually he'll have to leave.
那是辆雪佛兰
So, that's a Chevrolet.
等下 这是什么
Oh, hang on a second, what's this?
这是什么 什么
What's this? What's this?
看到了 那里有辆车
Okay, there's a car there. I can see it.
现在就在边上 等下
Now, just in the edge. Hang on.
一辆加大自由光 [Jeep车型]
A grand cherokee.
嗯 可能就是辆普通的自由光
Well, maybe just a cherokee.
不过肯定不是奔驰
But it's certainly not a Mercedes.
几点了 -2:44
What's the time? -  2:44.
所以我们已经等了大概四个小时了
So we've been here for, like, four hours?
我们都已经蹲守几天了
We've been waiting like this for days.
别说了
Come on.
这情形看起来他根本不会出门
And it seems like he'll never come out.
好吧 我看下 也是辆
Okay. Let me just check. It's also...
就是这个型号 还有白色底盘
It is the right type of car. It's got white plates.
等下 等下
Hang on. Hang on. Okay.
是他 就是他 千真万确
It's him. It's him. It's him. It's him.
他出来了 在这儿等着
He's coming out. Just wait here.
就在这儿坐着 没事儿的
Just sit here. All right, stay cool.
好了 我要
Okay, I'm gonna...
嗯 他在这里
Okay, he's up here.
他在右边这条道 他不是在左边吗
He's in the right-hand... Is he in the left-hand Lane?
是的
Yeah.
他还没开向右边 他在
He hasn't turned right. He's in...
哇 你和他就隔着一辆车
Whoa! You're one car behind him.
你就在他的 后视镜里
You're right in his... In his mirror now.
-我要喘不过气来了 -嗯 我也是
- I'm breathing heavily. - Yeah, same.
好的 好的 没事
Okay. Okay. It's cool.
我们就在他正后方 后退一点
We're right behind him now, so back off a bit,
我们不要靠太近
so we're not gonna be too close.
好的
Okay.
就后退 后退 大卫
Just stay... stay back. Stay back, David.
我们就停在他后面
We're gonna have to stop right behind him now.
你可能要把摄影机从三脚架上拿下来
You might have to take the camera off the tripod, dom.
对 请把摄影机拿开
Yeah, camera off tripod, please.
星巴克 完美
Starbucks? Okay, this is perfect.
好 他要出去一会儿
Okay. He'll be a while.
好了 我就过去等他出来谈一谈
Okay. I'm just gonna go and have conversation when he comes out.
你有我号码的 要需要打给我
You've... I've got my phone if you need me.
没问题
Okay.
我马上就要见到这个人了
I'm about to meet this man who's been
他威胁着众多人
such a threatening figure
也包括我
in so many lives, including my own,
我完全不知道应该期待什么
and I have simply no idea what to expect.
他出来了 -迪马托先生
He's coming out. - Mr. D'amato.
嗨 我是我是大卫 法瑞尔
Hi, it's Dave farrier.
嘿 你怎么样
Hey, how are you?
我就想简短地跟你说几句
I just wanted to talk to you briefly.
如果可以的话
If I could.
因为我有点 有点担心
Because I was just... I'm just worried about...
你寄给我的律师函
The legal letters you've sent me,
我就想我们能否
and I just wanted to know if we could
面对面谈一下
just talk about it face-to-face.
在这里
Is there?
我签的记者签证 所以我这么做没问题
I'm on a journalism visa, so I'm, I'm okay to be here.
我这么做没问题 不过我
I'm okay to be here. But I just...
我们能不能谈一点
Could we just talk a little bit about--
我就是想知道这都怎么回事
I just wanted to find out what's going on.
因为走之前我收到你说法庭上见
Because the last heard I was gonna be in a us court
新西兰的法庭上见
and a New Zealand court,
我就想面对面把这事儿理清
and I really just wanted to sort this out face-to-face.
我只是想
And I just want to sort of...
嗯 我来这儿不是来惹恼你的
I mean, I'm not here to antagonize.
我真心打算把这事处理好
I just genuinely want to be able to help out.
嗯 你确实说过你要起诉我
Well, you did say you were gonna sue me.
我就想把这事解决了
And I just wanna sort this issue out.
如果可以务必联系我
Could you contact me if possible?
我走的时候都感觉不知所云
I went away feeling numb.
迪马托很冷静 一直在说律师函的事
D'amato was calm, going instantly to legal threats,
我猜 他伪装成特里 伪装成简的时候
which is what he's always done, I suppose, as Terri,
或者他本来
as Jane,
就经常干这事
as himself.
经历了这一切 我忍不住好奇
But after all this, I still couldn't help but wonder
到底迪马托是不是
were we totally certain that d'amato
简或者黛比 难道真的是我们错了
really was Jane and Debbie? Could we be wrong?
所以我们又重回原点
So we went back to where it all started,
那300个
those 300 domain names
和Nederdietsen有关的域名
connected to the nederdietsen group.
在这时事情变得有些不可思议了
And that's when things went a little crazy.
那些域名之中
On one of those domain names
有一个目录
there was just a directory listing,
包含着一个叫做我的文件的文件夹
including a folder called "My documents".
看起来迪马托好像不小心
It looks like d'amato has accidently
把上百个他的私人文件都在
made hundreds of his private files public
互联网上公之于众了
on the Internet.
里面有Nederdietsen的注册表
There's d'amato's signature
是以迪马托的名义签的名
on a nederdietsen registration form.
还有一张他和雇佣调查我们的
There's also a contract with the investigation company
侦探公司的合同
he hired to look into us.
地址和简 奥布莱恩媒体
The address is exactly the same
在新西兰的希尔顿预定房间时用的地址
as the address used by Jane o'brien media
一模一样
when booking rooms at the Hilton in New Zealand.
还有那些黛比 库恩和简 奥布莱恩的
Then there are documents and signatures
签名和文件
for Debbie kuhn and Jane o'brien...
我们也找到了她的信用卡
Who's also got her own credit card.
结果证明迪马托真的在
And it turns out that d'amato
斯特拉大学2011年
did finally get that law degree,
拿到了法学学位
from hofstra university in 2011.
他一直在告诉那些男孩子们
He's also been telling the boys to enter the United States
靠旅游签证进入美国 就算他们接受了有偿工作 [违反移民条例]
on a tourist visa, even though they're working.
我终于明白
And it's finally clear to me
他是怎么建立被挠帝国的了
how he funds his tickling empire.
2012年底的时候
As of late 2012,
他的活期存款大概有六百万
he had almost six million in his checking account.
他的生活开销来自于他爸爸的
And his living expenses were being paid by a trust
信托基金
established by his father.
当她妈妈2014年去世的时候
He also inherited millions from his mother's estate
他继承了他妈妈的数百万遗产
when she died in 2014.
钱全部都是家里面的
It's all family money.
还有很多邮件
There are also lots of emails
是简 奥布莱恩的雇佣律师寄来的
sent from Jane o'brien's legal department.
想到这儿 我们打电话给了
With this in mind, we call in to see Romeo salta,
受雇于简 奥布莱恩的罗密欧 萨尔塔律师
the lawyer hired by Jane o'brien media
那个一直用诉讼威胁我们的律师
who's been sending us all the legal threats.
我们想问问他那些从他办公室寄出来的信
We want to ask him about the correspondence
是怎么回事
his office has sent us.
我觉着你应该会想看看
But I just thought you'd be curious to see...
在洛杉矶提起诉讼的这个案子
Things been issued in la county court,
这儿签的是你的名字
that's signed off here with your name.
这儿还有一封相同地址的邮件
There's another example of that with that email address.
嗯
Yeah.
那个 不是你寄的吧
To that, as opposed to you.
我是说 我们有一份由你发送的原件
I mean, we got the one from you originally,
这没什么好说的
which we... it's fine. We don't need to talk about that.
事情很简单 我只发过一封邮件
It's very simple. I only sent one.
我懂的
Yeah.
-这就是你的回答了 -对的
- There's your answer. - Yeah.
我会看看我能做什么的
I'll see what I can do to make those stop.
你们还在收到这种邮件吗
Have they stopped?
啊 现在没有了
Uh, we haven't heard anything for a little while.
但是他们在用你的地址
They're listing your address
作为企业的总部地址
as their corporate headquarters, though.
-我的吗 -对的 如果你看下这个的话
- My address? - Yeah, if you look at...
这是你办公室的地址
Your office.
简 奥布莱恩网
Janeobrienmedia.Com,
你的办公室地址被列为他们的企业总部地址
your address is listed as their corporate headquarters.
但是这不是我的网站啊
Yeah, but it's not my--
我知道 我知道 你看在网页最下方
No, no. On their website at the bottom.
但是这不是...
But it's not, um...
我不知道...
I don't know if it's...
这儿写着法律顾问办公室
It says "Office of corporate counsel
纽约总部
and New York headquarters."
好吧 这是 我的地址
Well, that's my address.
嗯
Yeah.
-但是 这不是他们的法律顾问办公室啊  -这真是难以置信
- But it's not their... - It's crazy. But it's...
呃 我是说啊 你觉着这个奇怪吗
Um, I mean, is this weird to you?
这人
That this person has taken on--
奇怪 当然奇怪
it is. Of course, it's weird.
我们收到的每一封萨尔塔寄来的法律意见书
Almost every legal letter we'd received from
几乎全是假的
from salta was fake.
就好像这么多跟迪马托有关的事
Like so many things connected to d'amato,
都是假的一样
they were all just lies,
都是为了解释他沉迷于挠痒视频扯出来的谎
lies to support his addiction to tickling videos.
我的这趟旅程始于对一项奇特运动的好奇
I started this journey curious about a bizarre sport
这项运动叫作挠痒痒耐力比赛
called competitive endurance tickling,
现在我知道了 虽说叫挠痒痒但是跟挠痒痒一毛钱关系都没有
but I now think this was never even about tickling.
这是一场关于权利 掌控和骚扰的游戏
This is about power, control and harassment.
有关一个人内心的扭曲
It's about one person's twistedness
以及这种扭曲能够到什么程度
and how far that can go.
一个人试图把自己的生活搞的充满铜臭味
One person who's managed to shelter himself with money
只是为了继续自己内心的执念
to keep his obsession going.
但是现在他的生活暴露在了大家面前
But now it's his life exposed.
他曾经一度以真面目现身摄像机前
For once, it's him on camera.
在我们离开美国之前
Before we leave America,
我还想打最后一个电话
there's one last phone call I want to make.
我们在文件里发现了这个名字
It's a name we found in the documents,
是大卫 迪马托一家还活着的家族成员之一
one of David d'amato's last surviving family members.
喂
Hello?
–噢 您好 是多萝西吗 –是我
- Oh, hi. Is that Dorothy? - Yes.
你好 我是大卫 法瑞尔
Oh, hi. My name's David farrier,
我是一名新西兰记者 您最近过得好吗
I'm a journalist from New Zealand. How are you?
–然后呢 –嗯 咱们继续
- Okay. - Yeah, good.
嘿 不好意思 对您来说这可能是
Hey, sorry, it's probably a bit of a strange call
意料之外的一通莫名其妙的电话
to receive out of the blue,
我正在做一个关于大卫 迪马托家族的系列故事
but I'm doing a story about, uh, David d'amato.
–噢 你准备怎么做 –呃
- Oh, in what way? - Um...
他有点 呃
He's been... it's the...
他挠痒痒的毛病好像有那么点复发
He's sort of back to the tickling stuff again.
噢 是吗
Oh, he is?
–嗯 是的 –天哪
- Yeah, he is. - Oh, god!
噢 我这么跟你说吧
Well, I will tell you that,
我跟他半毛钱关系都没有
um, I have no contact with him at all.
我是说 你觉得这些有个头吗
I mean, did you think all this had sort of come to an end?
我想过这个问题 当然会有结束的一天
I did think, of course, it came to an end,
因为他进过局子 我也很确信您一定知道这一点
because he served time, which I'm sure you know.
唔
Mm.
但是我有点不能理解 嗯
But I don't understand, um...
我不能理解他为什么又开始了
I don't understand why he went back to doing this.
我 有点震惊 他做这个事情有多久了
I'm, like, in shock. How long has he been doing this?
是根本就没停过
It's never stopped.
我觉得他可能有人格分裂
I think he has a split personality.
他就站在天才与癫狂的分界线上
He's like that fine line between genius and insanity.
我不知道他是同性恋还是无性恋
I don't know if he's gay or he's asexual,
但是就我所知 他从来没有交过女朋友
but he's never had a girlfriend that I ever knew of.
我以前问过我丈夫
I asked my husband once, um,
要是发现他是基佬会不会不高兴
if he would be upset if he found out he was gay.
他跟我说肯定会不高兴 但是也能克服
And he said that he would be upset but he would get over it.
但是他是我们的独子
But he was an only child,
然后你也知道 我丈夫很想抱孙辈的
and, you know, he wanted grandchildren.
他的童年非常非常奇怪
He had a very, very strange childhood.
以前那些小孩老是嘲笑他
The kids used to make fun of him all the time.
她以前 她 说的是他的生母
And she used to... She... his mother.
他跟他妈妈很亲密
He was very close to his mother.
他妈妈也把他保护得很好
And his mother was very protective of him.
她从不让他骑车或者滑雪 也不许他干别的事
She never let him ride a bike or go skiing or do anything
因为她害怕他会受伤
because she was always afraid that he would get hurt.
而且就我所知
And from what I understand,
孩子们以前很喜欢跑到他们家房子周围
the kids used to come around the house,
也常常取笑他
and they used to make fun of him.
有一次这些孩子把他锁在了学校的储物柜里
And once they locked him in a locker in school.
然后 你也知道 他是老师啊
And, you know, he was a teacher...
这帮孩子就把他丢出了学校
And they threw him out of school.
你明白吗 我以前有点怕他
You know, I was afraid of him,
因为我是自己一个人 怎么说呢 我就是有点怕
because I'm alone and, um... Yeah, I was afraid of him.
嗯 如你所见 我挺怕他的
So, you know, I'm afraid of him.